<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code &amp; Craft by Kasra</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Code &amp; Craft by Kasra</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 11:00:43 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Log Git Commands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/log-git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 11:00:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/log-git-commands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kepp a log of all your &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commands&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable no-inline-html --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;neo-financial&#34;&gt;Neo Financial&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: space-between;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Neo/card.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Card Details Screen&#34; style=&#34;width: 23%;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Neo/home-tab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Home Screen&#34; style=&#34;width: 23%;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Neo/investment.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Investment Screen&#34; style=&#34;width: 23%;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Neo/rewards.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rewards Screen&#34; style=&#34;width: 23%;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being among the pioneering members of the iOS development team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.neofinancial.com&#34;&gt;Neo Financial&lt;/a&gt;, I significantly influenced the direction of the Neo app&amp;rsquo;s development. Starting as an Intermediate Developer, my commitment, skills, and collaborative approach led to my promotion to Senior Developer within two years. During my time at Neo, I achieved several notable milestones, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the man behind the code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a part-time comedian to a captivatingly stubborn red Pembroke Welsh Corgi named Ginger, full-time iOS developer, and master of multitasking between family and Swift syntax.&#xA;My iOS journey began in 2013 when I had to make a walking app for my Masters project. Learning Objective-C in just three months was tough, but I fell in love with app development right away.&#xA;After graduation, I made an expense-tracking app called &amp;ldquo;My Cost&amp;rdquo;. I maintained it for a while until I decided to pursue a Ph.D. in computer science, focusing on finding anomalies in big data with neural networks.&#xA;Throughout my tenure as a freelance iOS developer, I had the privilege of collaborating with various companies, taking &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/&#34;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; from conception to completion. Each app listed below represents a culmination of my skills, creativity, and dedication to delivering high-quality mobile experiences. While I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on from contractor work, the responsibility for maintaining these apps now rests with other developers.&#xA;In 2020, I made the leap to become a full-time iOS developer and joined Neo Financial, a company dedicated to revolutionizing the banking experience for Canadians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
